Sivakumar Vunnam

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

	🔀 sivakumarvunnam1@gmail.com	+1-603-94	3-9002	Lewisville, Texas	
in	https://www.linkedin.com/in/sivakuma	arvunnam/ 🌐	https://siv	akumarvunnam.git	hub.io

SUMMARY

Successful DevOps Engineer with Over 5 years of professional Experience dedicated to Cloud, DevOps automation and Cloud Infrastructure(cost optimization, governance). I enjoy Designing, Implementing, and Supporting applications in the AWS, GCP cloud infrastructure. I'm driven and committed to providing solutions that satisfy engineering needs. I'm a highly motivated, productive team player looking to lead by example. Enthusiastic about exploring new services in the DevOps area. My greatest strength is my ability to thoroughly research a requirement and design a solution that is cost-effective, resilient, fault-tolerant, and highly available. Using my cloud expertise, have greatly contributed to multiple successful migrations to AWS from on-premise infrastructure.

SKILLS

Jenkins		Packer	
AWS		SonarQube	
Docker		Jfrog	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ
Kubernetes		Python	
Terraform	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	Yaml/Json	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bigcirc$
Shell Scripting		SaltStack	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bigcirc$
Vagrant		Ansible	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bigcirc$
Microsoft Azure	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ	EFK	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bigcirc$
Databases	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ	Prometheus	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ
Google Cloud (GCP)	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ	Grafana	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

EXPERIENCE

STAFF DEVOPS ENGINEER

Blackhawk Network Inc - Lewisville, Texas Sep 2018 - Present

- AWS Standardization: Standardizing CloudFormation templates across all environments for Hawk Marketplace, BHN Core Dev, Preproduction, Production migration to Oregon using Service Catalog. Core Production DR capability in Virginia for target platforms using Service Catalog.
- **Cost Management**: AWS account deprecation and decommission. Spot instances coverage >80% in all BHN Core Non-Prod accounts, Hawk Marketplace Non-Prod accounts. Reserved Instances coverage > 80% in all core Prod accounts with a stable baseline.
- Migration Applications from **AWS Classic Load Balancer to Application load Balancer** using single ALB with Multiple Target Group(HostHeader, Path) strategy to reduce cost.
- **CI/CD**: Jenkins Enterprise pipeline adoption for across BHN Organization using Jenkins Shared Libraries. Automated CI/CD for Marketplace Applications using Bitbucket, Jenkins, Jrog, SonarQube, S3, AWS Code Deploy.
- AWS Governance: AWS golden image creation using packer and Salt Stack (Linux and Windows) and adoption of AWS Linux
- Hawk Marketplace Migration: Extensively worked on AWS Migration for the project Hawk Incentives from IBM Data Center to AWS Oregon Region
- Email Microservice Implementation for Hawk Marketplace projects using Shotgun Framework (Terraform, AWS, EKS)
- Hawk Redeem implementation in AWS: Migrating application from Datacenter to AWS worked with

AWS cloud partners' Mactores team using CloudFormation.

• **Development tool consolidation**: Synergy/Marketplace Opensource Jenkins and bitbucket migration to Core BHN Cloud bees Enterprise Jenkins.

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

Saibersys Inc | Nexient Inc, Ann Arbor, MI Oct 2017 - Aug 2018

- AWS Migration for the project Hawk Incentives from IBM Data Center to AWS Oregon Region
- Handling day to day tickets opened in the rally ticketing system.
- Writing cloud formation templates for AWS migration to Automate the AWS Services VPC, Bastion hosts, PAN
 Data Server, Hawk Incentives Applications and Web servers with aws high availability and fault tolerance
 architecture
- Worked on infrastructure/apm monitoring solution new relic
- Worked on setting up logging Splunk for production and non-prod environment EFK
- Hand on knowledge in working Amazon web services (IAM, EC2, EBS, S3, Cloud Front, Autoscaling and Load Balancing, VPC, RDS, ROUTE 53)
- Setup and maintain the CI/CD using Jenkins for AWS Code Deploy and AWS Cloud Formation
- Extensively worked on writing the Code Builds for AMP-Studio React (UI). Configured it Nginx as a reverse proxy
- Working on implementing the Microservice called email microservice which connect the spring boot backend and send email templates to the customers.
- Did the POC with the (Terraform, EKS Cluster, Application Load Balancer, API gateway, Lambda, Aurora MySQL)
- Created CI/CD for Email Microservice

DevOps Engineer

Saibersys Inc | HGST a Western Digital, San Jose, CA Jul 2016 - Aug 2017

- Installation and configuring the EXSI server on Dell and Super Micro bare metal provisioning hardware's
- Configured Launched EXSI Server's as a Cluster using the VSphere and VCenter.
- Installation, configuring and administration the Linux VM's on ESXI servers Using Vagrant
- Implemented the automated factory installation on ActiveScale X100 and ActiveScale P100 hardware,
- Supporting TAAS (Test Drive as a Service) multiple geographical locations from Belgium, Las Vegas and San Jose.
- Working on container orchestration tools Kubernetes for Customizability, Scalability, and High availability of Jenkins
- Experience in writing the YAML files for Jenkins Job Builder for Dynamic Jenkins jobs configuration.
- Installation, configuration and administration experience in revision management tool Gitlab, Jenkins, Maven, Nexus, Docker, Docker Swarm
- Written Dockerfiles for to Isolate Java Spring Boot, Python, Nodejs, Angular Applications code in to docker images.
- To Build and Deploy the code created custom docker slave images with environment depencies
- Written scripts for Jenkins home backup daily into JFrog Artifactory
- Worked on POC to deploy TAAS on Kubernetes ecosystem and configured EFK to collect TAAS logs and stored it in centralized environment.

DevOps Engineer

Saibersys Inc | Cisco San Jose, CA Dec 2015 - Apr 2016

- Handling day to day tickets opened in JIRA ticketing system
- Setting up Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment process using Git, Jenkins, Maven, Nexus, SonarQube, Tomcat application sever s instances
- Working on Ansible to automate application deployments.
- Written Ansible playbooks to create a custom application environment for Java and DotNet Applications
- Experience In installing and configuring configuration management tool puppet. Experience in writing new Puppet Modules. Puppetizing the configurations across different environments.
- Experience in writing puppet modules for setting up new environments and for administration use.
- Working on puppet to automate Configuration management & Applications.
- Puppet to manage Web Applications, Config Files, Database, Users Mount Points, and Packages.

BUILD AND RELEASE ENGINEER

Unwired Labs, Hyderabad, Telangana Jan 2013 - Jul 2014

• Experience in Installation and configurations for Linux distributions operating system.

- Experience in working Agile Environment.
- Hands-on experience in Installation and Configuring and Administration tasks in Source code management tools like GIT, Subversion. Continuous integration tools like Jenkins, Hudson.
- Maintained protocol like TCP/IP, NIS, NFS, DNS, SNMP, VSFTP and DHCP FTP and Samba on Linux systems.
- Responsible for setting up Cron jobs scripts on production servers.
- Responsible for using build tools like Maven and Ant for the building of deploying the artifacts such as Jar, war & ear from source code.
- Responsible for storing the artifact's in Nexus repositories. After Building the code in Continuous Integration.
- Responsible for Installing and configuring setup for clustered environment with Apache Tomcat Application Server for automatic Deployment.
- Implemented a Continuous Delivery framework using Jenkins, Maven, Nexus and Chef in Linux environment.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Rivier University - Nashua, NH Aug 2014 - Dec 2015

• GPA - 3.8/4.0

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, COMPUTER SCIENCE

Acharya Nagarjuna University - Guntur, AP Aug 2009 - May 2013

• CGPA - 3.3/4.0

CERTIFICATION

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associat (saa-c01)

Amazon Web Services - 2018

PERSONAL SKILLS

Problem solving		Excellent organisational	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ
Team Leader	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	skills	
Planning strategically		Attention to detail	

REFERAL

Available on request.